{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Information Management",
    "Term": "Prefinals",
    "Title": "Introduction to SQL - Part 1",
    "LastModified": "17 May 2024",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Any external links/handouts should be referenced here"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is a specific request for data manipulation issued by the end-user or the application to the DBMS?",
      "answer": "Query",
      "choices": [
        "SQL",
        "Table",
        "Console",
        "Query"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does SQL stand for?",
      "answer": "Structured Query Language",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language",
        "Structured Query Link",
        "Structured Queing Language",
        "System Query Language"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How is SQL pronounced?",
      "answer": "Pronounced as S-Q-L or “sequel”",
      "choices": [
        "Pronounced as S-Q-L or “sequel”",
        "Pronounced as ES-QL",
        "Pronounced as ES-QLI",
        "Pronounced as S-QLI"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL data types does bigint, bit, decimal, int, money, numeric belong to?",
      "answer": "Exact numeric",
      "choices": [
        "Exact numeric",
        "Approximate numeric",
        "Binary strings",
        "Arithmetic"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL data types does float, real belong to?",
      "answer": "Approximate numeric",
      "choices": [
        "Approximate numeric",
        "Comparison",
        "Compound",
        "Logical"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL data types does date, datetime, time belong to?",
      "answer": "Date and time",
      "choices": [
        "Date and time",
        "Query",
        "Character strings",
        "Approximate numeric"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL data types does char, text, varchar belong to?",
      "answer": "Character strings",
      "choices": [
        "Character strings",
        "Unicode character strings",
        "Binary strings",
        "Date and time"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL data types does nchar, ntext, nvarchar belong to?",
      "answer": "Unicode character strings",
      "choices": [
        "Unicode character strings",
        "Binary strings",
        "Arithmetic",
        "Comparison"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL data types does binary, image, varbinary belong to?",
      "answer": "Binary strings",
      "choices": [
        "Binary strings",
        "Arithmetic",
        "Comparison",
        "Logical"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL operators does '+, -, *, /, %' belong to?",
      "answer": "Arithmetic",
      "choices": [
        "Binary strings",
        "Arithmetic",
        "Comparison",
        "Logical"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL operators does '=, &gt;, &lt;, &gt;=, &lt;=, &lt;&gt;' belong to?",
      "answer": "Comparison",
      "choices": [
        "Compound",
        "Arithmetic",
        "Comparison",
        "Logical"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL operators does '+=, -=, *=, /=, %=' belong to?",
      "answer": "Compound",
      "choices": [
        "Compound",
        "Arithmetic",
        "Comparison",
        "Logical"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What category of SQL operators does 'AND, OR, NOT, LIKE, IN, BETWEEN, EXISTS, ANY, ALL' belong to?",
      "answer": "Logical",
      "choices": [
        "Binary strings",
        "Arithmetic",
        "Comparison",
        "Logical"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to create a new database with a specific name?",
      "answer": "CREATE DATABASE database_name;",
      "choices": [
        "CREATE DATABASE database_name;",
        "DROP DATABASE myDB;",
        "DROP DATABASE",
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command used to create a new database?",
      "answer": "CREATE DATABASE",
      "choices": [
        "CREATE DATABASE",
        "DROP DATABASE",
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);",
        "DROP TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to create a new database named ‘myDB’?",
      "answer": "CREATE DATABASE myDB;",
      "choices": [
        "CREATE DATABASE myDB;",
        "CREATE DATABASE database_name;",
        "DROP DATABASE",
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command used to delete an existing database?",
      "answer": "DROP DATABASE",
      "choices": [
        "DROP DATABASE",
        "CREATE DATABASE myDB;",
        "CREATE DATABASE database_name;",
        "ALTER DATABASE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to create a new table with specific columns and data types?",
      "answer": "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);",
      "choices": [
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);",
        "DROP TABLE",
        "DROP TABLE table_name;",
        "DROP TABLE Students;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command used to delete an existing table?",
      "answer": "DROP TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "DROP TABLE",
        "DROP TABLE table_name;",
        "DROP TABLE Students;",
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to delete a specific table?",
      "answer": "DROP TABLE table_name;",
      "choices": [
        "DROP TABLE table_name;",
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);",
        "DROP TABLE Students;",
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to delete a table named ‘Students’?",
      "answer": "DROP TABLE Students;",
      "choices": [
        "DROP TABLE Students;",
        "DROP TABLE",
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);",
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to delete only the data in the ‘Students’ table?",
      "answer": "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;",
      "choices": [
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;",
        "DROP TABLE table_name;",
        "DROP TABLE",
        "CREATE TABLE table_name (column1 datatype, …);"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command used to add, delete, or modify columns in an existing table?",
      "answer": "ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "ALTER TABLE",
        "DROP TABLE Students;",
        "DROP TABLE table_name;",
        "DROP TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to add a column to a specific table?",
      "answer": "ALTER TABLE table_name ADD column datatype;",
      "choices": [
        "ALTER TABLE table_name ADD column datatype;",
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;",
        "DROP TABLE Students;",
        "DROP TABLE table_name;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to delete a column from a specific table?",
      "answer": "ALTER TABLE table_name DROP COLUMN column;",
      "choices": [
        "ALTER TABLE table_name DROP COLUMN column;",
        "ALTER TABLE",
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;",
        "DROP TABLE Students;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SQL command to modify a column in a specific table?",
      "answer": "ALTER TABLE table_name ALTER COLUMN column datatype;",
      "choices": [
        "ALTER TABLE table_name ALTER COLUMN column datatype;",
        "ALTER TABLE table_name ADD column datatype;",
        "ALTER TABLE",
        "TRUNCATE TABLE Students;"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint ensures that a column cannot have a NULL value upon creating a table?",
      "answer": "NOT NULL on CREATE TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "NOT NULL on CREATE TABLE",
        "NOT NULL on ALTER TABLE",
        "UNIQUE on CREATE TABLE",
        "UNIQUE on ALTER TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint ensures that a column in an existing table cannot have a NULL value?",
      "answer": "NOT NULL on ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "NOT NULL on ALTER TABLE",
        "UNIQUE on CREATE TABLE",
        "UNIQUE on ALTER TABLE",
        "PRIMARY KEY on CREATE TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint ensures that all values in a column are different upon creating a table?",
      "answer": "UNIQUE on CREATE TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "UNIQUE on CREATE TABLE",
        "UNIQUE on ALTER TABLE",
        "PRIMARY KEY on CREATE TABLE",
        "PRIMARY KEY on ALTER TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint creates a UNIQUE constraint on a column of an existing table?",
      "answer": "UNIQUE on ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "UNIQUE on ALTER TABLE",
        "PRIMARY KEY on CREATE TABLE",
        "PRIMARY KEY on ALTER TABLE",
        "FOREIGN KEY on CREATE TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint uniquely identifies each row in a table?",
      "answer": "PRIMARY KEY on CREATE TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "PRIMARY KEY on CREATE TABLE",
        "PRIMARY KEY on ALTER TABLE",
        "FOREIGN KEY on CREATE TABLE",
        "FOREIGN KEY on ALTER TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint creates a PRIMARY KEY constraint on a column of an existing table?",
      "answer": "PRIMARY KEY on ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "PRIMARY KEY on ALTER TABLE",
        "FOREIGN KEY on CREATE TABLE",
        "FOREIGN KEY on ALTER TABLE",
        "CHECK on CREATE TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint uniquely identifies a row in another table?",
      "answer": "FOREIGN KEY on CREATE TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "FOREIGN KEY on CREATE TABLE",
        "FOREIGN KEY on ALTER TABLE",
        "CHECK on CREATE TABLE",
        "CHECK on ALTER TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint creates a FOREIGN KEY constraint on a column of an existing table?",
      "answer": "FOREIGN KEY on ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "FOREIGN KEY on ALTER TABLE",
        "CHECK on CREATE TABLE",
        "CHECK on ALTER TABLE",
        "DEFAULT on CREATE TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint ensures that all values in a column satisfy a specific condition upon creating a table?",
      "answer": "CHECK on CREATE TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "CHECK on CREATE TABLE",
        "CHECK on ALTER TABLE",
        "DEFAULT on CREATE TABLE",
        "DEFAULT on ALTER TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint ensures that all values in a column of an existing table satisfy a specific condition?",
      "answer": "CHECK on ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "CHECK on ALTER TABLE",
        "DEFAULT on CREATE TABLE",
        "DEFAULT on ALTER TABLE",
        "NOT NULL on CREATE TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint sets a default value for a column when there is no value specified upon creating a table?",
      "answer": "DEFAULT on CREATE TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "DEFAULT on CREATE TABLE",
        "DEFAULT on ALTER TABLE",
        "NOT NULL on CREATE TABLE",
        "NOT NULL on ALTER TABLE"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What SQL constraint sets a default value for a column of an existing table when there is no value specified?",
      "answer": "DEFAULT on ALTER TABLE",
      "choices": [
        "DEFAULT on ALTER TABLE",
        "NOT NULL on CREATE TABLE",
        "NOT NULL on ALTER TABLE",
        "UNIQUE on CREATE TABLE"
      ]
    }
  ]
}
